字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
我们打败极速了
We just beat Zoom.
可我为什么有挫败感
Why does it feel like I just lost?
我从来没这么撕心裂肺过
I feel more broken than I've ever felt.
不管你要去哪里
Wherever you need to go,
不管你要做什么  都行
whatever you need to do, do it.
我会在这里等你回来
I'll be here.
你安全了
You're safe.
我们要怎么称呼这个美丽新世界呢
So what should we call this brave new world?
我想的是闪点
I was thinking Flashpoint.
我叫爱德华·克拉里斯
My name is Edward Clariss.
竞争者应该知道对方的名字
Rivals should know each other's names.
仿佛我一想起过去的一段记忆
It's like I'll be thinking of a moment
然后它就消失了
from my past and it vanishes.
这里不是你的家  巴里
This isn't your home, Barry.
这是个幻影
It's a mirage.
事情恢复原样了
Things are back to how they should be.
反正对我而言是  对你而言
Well, for me, anyway. For you?
只能等你去探索了
I guess you'll just have to wait and find out.
爱瑞丝在哪里
Where's Iris?
你知道爱瑞丝不在这里
You know Iris isn't here.
他们冷战了  巴里
They don't talk, Barry.
天呐  我做了什么
Oh, God. What did I do?
我犯了一个大错
I made a big mistake.
我之前实在是受不了了
I just couldn't take it anymore, you know?
极速的事  我父亲死了
What happened with Zoom, my dad dying,
母亲被杀  我成为了闪电侠
my mother's death, me becoming The Flash.
所有的一切  我想要新的生活
All of it. I wanted a new life.
想要重新开始  也这么做了
I wanted to start over. And that's what I did.
不知怎么我却让事情变得更糟了
But somehow I-I made things worse.
-不是吧  -我重设了所有事
- No. - So I reset everything.
让一切回到了原来的样子
I put everything back to the way that it was before.
可是有些事却不一样了
Except some things weren't the same anymore.
一点都不一样
Not even a little bit.
慢慢说
Slow down.
喘口气
Take a breath.
你说得太快了
You were talking way too fast.
-是的  -发生了什么
- Yeah. - What happened?
我真的搞砸了  费利西蒂
I really screwed up, Felicity.
而且这次不知道我能不能弥补
And this time I don't know if I can fix it.
闪电侠
第三季
第二集
好吧  让我理一下
Okay, let me get this straight.
-你回到过去  -是的
- You ran back in time? - Yeah.
阻止了逆闪电杀死你妈妈
Stopped Reverse-Flash from killing your mom
生活在你父母都还活着的
and then lived in an alternate reality
另一个现实里
where both your parents were alive?
是的
Yeah.
然后你恢复了时间线
And then you restored the timeline,
回到你离开的那个时刻
came back to the moment you left,
-却发现事情都变了  -没错
- and noticed that things were different? - Exactly.
只要你穿越时间就会这样吗
Does that just happen when you travel through time?
事情就像那样变了吗
Do things just change like that?
不  不是这样的
No, I mean, not like this.
我不知道  我不知道  费利西蒂
Not on--I don't know. I don't know Felicity.
我不知道我该怎么做
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
好吧  你先跟我说一遍
Okay, why don't you just run me through--
慢慢说发生了什么
walk me through what happened?
我们再想想办法解决
And we'll, we'll try and figure it out.
都有什么改变了
So what changed?
昨晚我一回来
I knew once I got back last night
就感觉有事情变了
some things had changed,
但在我弄清变了多少之前
but before I could figure out exactly how much,
一大早我就得去阻止某个人
I had to deal with someone this morning.
你骑着这玩意
You are not gonna get too far
再也跑不远了  是吧
on that thing anymore, are you?
我会把你偷的这些东西
I will be taking these back to the jewelry store
还给珠宝店
you stole them from.
不过  这些你可以留下
But, you can keep these if you'd like.
祝你好运
Good luck with that.
处理完他的事后  我去了尖端科研实验室
After he was taken care of, I went to S.T.A.R. Labs,
就在这个时候
and that's when I found out
我才发现好多事情已经改变了
a lot more had changed than I realized.
什么样的蠢蛋会觉得
What kind of idiot still thinks
我没有子弹跑得快
I can't outrun bullets?
应该把他放到罪犯海报上
That guy should be the criminal poster boy
告诉别人别跟闪电侠作对
for what not to do against The Flash.
那我们应该叫他什么
So what are we gonna call him?
-绰号吗  -是的
- You mean like a nickname? - Yeah.
这是西斯科的活  他很擅长
Cisco does it for all of them, he's like the master of it.
总不能叫他"骑摩托车的嫌犯"吧
Can't just call him Suspect on a Motorcycle,
对吧  你觉得呢
Right? What do you think?
-我不知道  -听听这个
- I don't know. - I'll take this one.
神钩小贼  蹩脚小盗
The Crook. Lame?
-扒手  -窃贼怎么样
- A Five-Finger-- - How about Thief?
他抢别人的东西  就叫他窃贼吧
He robs stuff. Let's just call him Thief.
我去健身房了  失陪
Gotta get to the gym. Excuse me.
健身房  他现在开始锻炼了吗
The gym? Is he--is he, like, working out now or--
巴里  有的时候  你的笑话
You know, Barry, sometimes your jokes
一点都不好笑
just aren't very funny.
我  我还是回报社吧
I should--I should get back to the paper.
没关系  我本来也要走了
It's okay. I was just leaving.
各位  乔  对不起
Hey, guys--hey, Joe. Look, hey, I'm sorry.
我知道你俩现在
Look, I just, I know you guys aren't speaking
正在冷战  可是我在想
to each other right now, but I was just thinking
能不能谈一会儿到底为什么
maybe we could talk about why that is for a minute. I--
-不行  -伙计
- No. - Dude.
-不想谈  -好吧  对不起  听我说
- No, we can't. - Okay, I'm sorry. I just-- look.
抱歉  我只是想  我不知道
I'm sorry, I just thought, I don't know,
如果你俩能把事情说开
maybe it would be good for you guys just to...
会有好处的
hear it said out loud.
这是因为他所做的事  巴里  不是因为我
This is because of what he did, Barry, not me.
-爱瑞丝  -怎么了
- Iris. - What?
你还能说什么
What could you possibly have to say?
回警局见  好吧
I'll just see you at the station, all right?
抓到窃贼  干得漂亮
Nice job with, Thief.
-顺便送我去中城大学  -好的
- Give me a lift to CCU? - Sure.
你还在读工程学
So you're still taking engineering classes.
-是的  -很好
- Yeah. - Yeah, cool.
好的  祝你有个好成绩
All right, well, good-- good luck with that.
-你怎么了  -没怎么
- What is wrong with you? - Nothing.
要我像不理他一样也不理你吗
Are you trying to make me as mad at you as I am at him?
不不  我很抱歉  我
No, no, look, I'm-- I'm sorry, I--
我不太明白你为什么对他那么生气
I guess I don't fully understand why you're so upset at him.
那或许你就不应该再提这事
Then maybe you shouldn't bring it up again.
好吧
Yeah.
谈谈我俩怎么样
How about we talk about us instead?
我们  你是指我和你
Us? You--you mean you and me,
要不要试试看
like, trying this?
我觉得最近
I just thought with everything
发生了这么多事
that's happened lately and everything
你经历了这么多事
that you've been through,
我只想确定你的感觉没变
I wanted to make sure that you still felt the same.
爱瑞丝  我都照你说的去做了
Well, Iris, I did what you said.
我去了该去的地方
I went where I needed to go,
做了该做的事
I did what I needed to do,
我准备好了
and I'm ready.
我从来没叫你这么做
I never told you to do that.
我们打败极速后
Yeah, no, you did-- on the porch,
你在门廊跟我说的  然后你...
right after we beat Zoom, right before you--
-你亲了爱瑞丝  -事情变了
- Wow, you kissed Iris. - Well, not anymore.
我亲了爱瑞丝·韦斯特两次
I've kissed Iris West twice,
而我把那两条时间线都抹去了
and I have managed to erase both times from existence.
我讨厌发生这种事
Man, I hate it when that happens.
这还不是今天最严重的事
That's just the least of my problems today.
乔  我能和你说两句话吗
Joe, hey-hey, man, um, can we talk for a second?
我要把这个拿去给辛格
Yeah, I just gotta drop this off for Singh.
辛格队长回来了吗  好极了
Oh, Captain Singh's back? That's just terrific.
怎么了  他去哪了吗
Yeah, why, did he go somewhere?
没  也许吧  我不知道
No-- maybe. I don't know, I--
蒙面兜帽会让你大脑窒息吗
Is that cowl cutting off all the oxygen in your brain?
什么  不会啊  为什么这么问
What? No, I'm fine. Why? Why?
因为你最近的表现很奇怪
Because you've been acting real odd lately.
昨晚问爱瑞丝为什么不在家
Asking why Iris wasn't at the house last night.
今早在尖端科研实验室又很奇怪
And that stunt you pulled at S.T.A.R. Labs this morning.
你很清楚她为什么不和我说话
You know damn well why she's not talking to me.
当然知道  因为
Of course. Uh, because sh--
因为我该跟她说她母亲还活着
Because I should have told her her mother was alive
但我没说
but I didn't.
但她不是原谅你了吗
Yeah, but she forgave you for that.
谁都知道她会原谅的
One would think that she would have.
我不知道她会不会原谅我
I don't know if she ever will or not,
但你插手干预也于事无补  巴仔
but you sticking your nose into it isn't helping, Bar.
-有心就行了  -我...好吧
- Good intentions and all. - I was-- okay.
今早我们又发现了一具外壳
We found another husk this morning.
外壳
Husk?
辛格要求尽快处理
Singh wants this processed ASAP.
朱利安·艾伯特
超能力者犯罪现场鉴证专家
市里出现的那些人皮壳
Yes, the skin husks we've been finding around the city
我们认为是从超能力者身上蜕下来的
are the ones we think are attached to the meta-humans.
这已经是第四具了
This is now the fourth one.
巴里·艾伦
犯罪现场鉴证员
在第五具出现之前
Well, let's figure out what's happening
赶紧查清楚吧
before there's a fifth.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
沉住气
Deep breaths.
你好
Hello?
你好  艾伦先生
Yes. Hello, Mr. Allen.
你还在这里  但是不必了
I can still see you're there and no,
我不需要你的帮忙  谢谢
I don't want your help, thank you.
你怎么在这里  朱利安·艾伯特
What are you doing here, Julian Albert,
超能力者犯罪现场鉴证专家
meta-human CSI specialist?
我和你说过超能力者大会只有两天
I did tell you the meta-human conference was only for two days.
好吧  但是这里
Okay, but this is--
很遗憾这里还是我们的实验室
Still our lab... unfortunately.
市里把我调来这里之前  忘记提到
Yes, County forgot to mention that significant detail
这么重要的细节  但是事已至此
before assigning me, but here we are.
看来我们不仅要成为室友
Looks like you and I get to be roomies
而且比我们希望的还要久
for a little longer than we'd hoped.
室友
Roomies.
有新人来上班
There's a whole new guy at work
你完全不知道吗
that you didn't even know about?
不知道  他在那都快工作了一年
Yeah. And he's worked there for almost a year.
而且他很不喜欢我
And he doesn't like me very much, apparently.
怎么可能呢  没人不喜欢巴里·艾伦
Well, that's impossible. Everybody likes Barry Allen.
你就像布丁  人人都喜欢布丁
You're like pudding. Everybody likes pudding.
不是所有的人
Not everyone.
三十七
37.
我讨厌我们从不交谈
I hated that we never spoke.
我想让我最苦恼的事情是
I think the thing that haunts me the most is the fact
我从来没和他说我爱他
that I never told him I loved him.
或是仰慕他
Or that I idolized him.
我一直都记得丹堤
I have memories of Dante all the time.
但这些回忆感觉不像礼物
But they don't feel like gifts.
而像是在提醒我
They feel like reminders...
我做错的事
of what I did wrong,
我没法再拥有跟丹堤一起的记忆了
and how I'll never make another memory with Dante again.
失陪一阵
Excuse me.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
等等  你现在才来关心我吗
Oh, wait a second. Now you wanna be there for me?
我只是试着去理解
I'm just trying to understand.
我哥哥死了
My brother's dead.
没什么好理解的
There's nothing to understand.
门在那
Exit's that way.
所以你改变了时间线
So you altered the timeline,
乔和爱瑞丝在冷战
Joe and Iris don't talk anymore,
警局里的新同事
there's a guy at work-- a new guy--
不喜欢你
who doesn't like you,
你没亲过爱瑞丝
you never kissed Iris,
西斯科的哥哥死了
and Cisco's brother is dead.
无可否认  这些都是问题
Admittedly, that is an issue.
如果还有更多的问题呢
And what if there's more?
这里有任何改变吗
Well, has anything here changed?
没  我不知道
No, I don't know. I mean,
一切貌似都没变吧
everything seems the same, I think.
那就好
Good.
我能用用... 等等
Can I use-- hold on.
我会非常小心的
I'll be real careful.
我会用  别担心  我会用
I got it, don't worry. I got it.
我也不知道  一切似乎很正常
Yeah, I don't know-- I mean, everything looks okay.
等等
Wait.
狄格抱着的小孩子是谁
Who's that young boy with Dig?
不是吧  他之前没有孩子吗
No way. He didn't have kid before?
他之前有孩子  有的
No, he had a kid. He has-- he has a kid.
是小莎拉
Yeah, it was baby Sara.
这是小约翰
Baby John.
-不  -不是吧
- No. - Are you--
天呐  这真会影响到我们
Oh, my God. It really can affect us.
这样吧  我不想再知道了
Okay, you know what? I don't wanna know anymore.
我知道你的压力很大
Okay, I know this is a lot of pressure,
但是事情都会好起来的
but everything's gonna be all right.
我搞乱了所有人的生活
I screwed up everyone's life.
也许你该告诉他们
Yeah, well, maybe you should tell them.
我不会告诉他们的
I'm not gonna tell them.
说出来又有什么用呢
I mean, how is that gonna help?
只会让事情变得更糟糕
That's just gonna make everything worse.
我不知道该怎么补救
I mean-- I don't know how to fix this.
你会想出办法的
Okay, well, you're gonna figure it out.
如果我从你身上学到了什么
If there's one thing I've learned from you,
那就是与你一起  一切都有可能
is that with you, anything is possible.
为什么  因为我是闪电侠吗
Why? 'Cause I'm The Flash?
不  因为你是巴里·艾伦
No. Because you are Barry Allen.
亲切  可爱  善良的巴里·艾伦
And sweet, loving, kind Barry Allen
人人都喜欢
that everybody likes,
那个就像布丁一样的巴里·艾伦
the Barry Allen who's just like pudding,
能补救这一切
can fix this.
所以去补救吧
So go and fix this.
好
Yeah.
好的  你说得对
Okay, you're right. Yeah.
-快去  -现在吗
- Now! - Right now?
-是的  -好吧  好的
- Yes! - Okay, all right.
停车
Stop!
来找我
Find me.
谁  找谁
Who? Who?
炼金术师
我是炼金术师
I am Alchemy.
我出现幻觉
I have visions...
看到另一种人生
of another life.
求你让幻觉停止
Please, make them stop.
这真的就是你想要的吗
Is that what you really want?
真的想让幻觉停止
To make the visions stop?
还是说想让它们成真
Or do you want them to come true?
再次变快
To be fast again?
-再次获得速度  -是的
- To have speed? - Yes.
你想要那另一种人生吗
Do you want that other life?
那就是我想要的
That's what I want.
你将再次获得超能力
Once again, you will have power.
并且没有人能成为你的竞争者
And no man will be your rival.
朱利安  我想你或许需要些帮助
Julian, I thought you could use some help on this one.
你知道  人多智广什么的
You know, the two heads thing and all.
我不需要帮助  警探
I don't need any help, Detective.
尤其是他的
Especially from him.
-那是什么  -又一具表皮外壳  艾伦
- What is that? - Another epidermal husk, Allen.
一具完整的人皮
A fully intact human pelt,
除了角质层什么都没有
comprised of nothing but the stratum corneum.
你懂我的意思了吧
You see what I mean?
关于成因我们目前有什么推测吗
Do we have any theories as to what's causing them?
我大胆假设一下
Well, I'll take a wild guess at it
和前四具外壳的成因一样
and say it's the same thing that created the last four husks.
可能因为中毒性表皮坏死松解症才脱皮的
Spalling could be caused from toxic epidermal necrolysis,
或者可能是由强辐射暴露引起的
or maybe some kind of moist desquamation
某种湿性脱皮
from intense radiation exposure.
-我们遇到很多  -辐射性超能力者
- We've had a lot of... - Radioactive metas.
谢谢你了  艾伦  我研究过所有案例
Yes, thank you, Allen. I've read all the case studies.
这样吧  等我搞明白了
I'll tell you what, when I figure it out,
我再给你解释  行吗
I'll enlighten you then, shall I?
谢了
Thanks.
去年我是怎么和这人合作的
How have I worked with this guy for the past year?
你总是这么说
Yeah, you say that all the time.
那是一定的
I'm sure I do.
朱利安
Julian?
你确定不需要巴里
Are you certain that Barry can't
取个样本什么的加快进度吗
take a sample or something to speed things along?
我确定  警探
I'm sure, Detective.
非常确定
Quite sure.
你最好把这个拿到尖端科研实验室
You might wanna get that to S.T.A.R. Labs.
好
Yeah.
这样本可不多
You know, there's really not that much here.
是  我知道  就只是触碰DNA样本
Yeah, no, I know. It's basically touch DNA.
这还是偷来的  因为我们超能力者专家
I had to steal the sample because our meta-human expert
不想让我取样
wouldn't let me take one.
你是说朱利安·艾伯特
Oh, you mean Julian Albert?
是啊  你认识他
Yeah, you know him?
是啊  我们认识有段时间了
Yeah, we've known him for a while.
他最棒了
He's the best.
-要我帮忙吗  -不用  我想我能处理
- You need me? - No, I think I got this.
-谢谢了  -好吧
- But thank you. - Okay.
西斯科跟我说昨晚
Cisco told me you showed up
在他的丧亲交流会上看到你了
to his bereavement group last night.
是啊  没错
Yeah, I did.
他有没有告诉你结果不太好
He also tell you it didn't go so well?
丹堤被酒驾司机撞死
It's only been a few months since Dante
才过了几个月而已
was killed by that drunk driver.
我想他还需要些时间接受现实
I'm sure he just needs a little bit more time.
等等  他为什么生我的气
Wait, why is he so mad at me?
我可不掺和你俩这事
Oh, no. I'm staying out of that.
凯特  其他人不在的时候
Cait, he'll-he'll barely look at me
他都不正眼看我
unless other people are in the room.
也许有别人会更加容易一些
Maybe it's just easier when the rest of us are around.
你觉得能不能说服他
Do you think maybe you could convince him
今晚和你一起来我家吃个晚饭
to come with you to my house for dinner tonight?
-为什么  -我就可以试着修复我俩的关系
- Why? - So I can try to fix things between us,
也许还能修复乔和爱瑞丝的关系
maybe between Joe and Iris, too.
大家再次聚在一个屋里
Just all of us together again in one room
想办法彻底解决这些问题
and try to work this out once and for all.
你能帮帮忙吗
Think you can do that?
好
Okay.
但你要怎么让乔和爱瑞丝过去
But how are you gonna get Joe and Iris there?
乔  乔
Joe? Hey, Joe.
我和爱瑞丝谈过了
So I talked to Iris
她有些事想和你说
and she just has a few things that she wants to say to you.
巴仔  我不是告诉过你别管了吗
Bar, I thought I told you to stay out of this.
不不不  这都是因为她  我发誓
Oh, no, no, no. This was all her, I swear.
所以她突然就
So she just, out of the blue,
决定想和我谈谈了
decided now she wants to talk to me?
所以乔说他会给你
So Joe said that he'd give you
关于外壳的资料来帮你写报道
what you need about the husks for a story.
什么  他突然就决定告诉我了
What? He just decided, out of the blue, to tell me?
警局里的人都守口如瓶
No one at the precinct will say anything.
-就连朱利安也是  -我真讨厌那家伙
- Even Julian. - Oh, I hate that guy.
你总是这么说
Yeah, you always say that.
他想要什么时候谈
When does he want to do it?
今晚  在家
Uh, tonight, at the house.
他说给你做你最喜欢吃的
He said he's making your favorite.
好吧  他是彻底疯了
Okay, he's out of his mind.
他知道我是不会回去的
He knows I will not go back there,
哪怕他做了埃丝特祖母拿手好菜  所以
even if he does make one of Grandma Esther's recipes, so...
什么时候
When?
今晚  是今晚
Uh, tonight. Tonight, yeah.
-在家里  -在家
- Um, at the house. - At the house?
是啊
Yeah.
她发誓她再也不会踏进那房子了
She vowed she'd never set foot in the house again.
除非你做了晚餐
Unless you made dinner.
-晚餐  -是啊  就像以前
- Dinner? - Yeah, like old times.
就是她最喜欢那个
So, one of her favorites,
或许做道埃丝特祖母的拿手好菜
like Grandma Esther's recipes, maybe.
好吧  我想我可以做点什么
Okay. I suppose I can make something.
要什么
Which dish?
他说会做鸡肉
He said he'd make the chicken.
我讨厌鸡肉  我爱吃面
I hate the chicken. I like the noodles.
-面条  好的  -你怎么气喘吁吁的
- Oh, noodles, okay. - Why are you out of breath?
我没有气喘吁吁的啊  乔还说
I'm not out of breath. Uh, Joe also thought
可能为了缓和一下气氛
maybe just to take some pressure off
他还邀请凯特琳和西斯科一起
that he'd invite Caitlin and Cisco.
-好吧  几点啊  -7点
- Okay, um, what time? - Uh, 7:00.
好的
All right.
对了  7点就行
7:00 will work, by the way.
好  吃什么
Okay, but which dish?
我在想  为了能缓和一下气氛
I mean, I was thinking maybe to take some pressure off,
或许可以邀请凯特琳和西斯科
you could invite Caitlin and Cisco.
这是个好主意
That's a good idea,
要是真要吃  那我就得开始准备了
'cause if we're gonna do this, I gotta get started.
收到  没问题
Yeah, I got it. No problem, yeah.
-巴里  -怎么了
- Bar? - Yeah?
-吃什么啊  -吃面
- Which dish? - Noodle dish.
是的  吃面
Yeah, noodle dish.
这感觉真棒 对吧
This hits the spot, huh?
你可以去感谢埃丝特祖母
You can thank Grandma Esther.
不是  面挺好的  我是说
No, I mean, it's good. I just meant, um...
我们大家都在这里  聚集了
all of us, actually, just here, together.
我在想  也许我们可以
I was actually thinking, um, that maybe it'd be fun
一起出去旅行几天什么的
if we all went away together for a few days.
就像个小闪电侠团队旅行
Just like a little Team Flash vacay.
-然后呢  -联络联络感情
- And do what? - Bond.
-和好如初  -你是说让步
- Reconnect. - You mean like a retreat?
-不是  -还有什么信任训练吗
- Nah. - With trust exercises?
六人行  注定失败
Epic fail, party of six.
我只是  觉得我们这个团队
I just--I just feel like we're not the team
没有以前那么好  或是能更好
that we were or can be.
没人赞成吗
No one?
我倒是赞成
I'd be down for it.
真好
Okay.
那除了沃利
So other than Wally,
就只有我觉得这是个好主意了吗
I'm the only one that thinks that's a good idea?
我觉得闪电侠不应该放假
I don't think The Flash really takes vacations.
尤其是在镇上出了这么多外壳的时候
Especially with all these husks showing up all over town.
说到外壳  我很高兴你终于决定
Speaking of husks, I'm glad you're finally ready
开诚布公了
to open up about them.
爱瑞丝  我说了  我不能
Iris, I already told you, I can't tell you
告诉你案子的事
anything about this case.
是吗
Oh, really?
通知我的时候可不是这么说的
Because that's not what I was told.
奇怪  我也以为
Strange. I was under the impression
是你有话跟我说呢
you had some things to say to me, too.
对吧  巴里
Isn't that right, Bar?
早告诉你了  注定失败
Told you. Epic fail.
好吧  是的  这都是我安排的
Okay, look, yeah. I arranged this.
是我把大家聚到了一起  抱歉  各位
I put all this together. I'm sorry, guys.
我只是  我们不像个团队
Look, I just-- we're not acting like a team,
我只是希望能回到过去的样子  好好的
and I just wanted things back to how they were. Just fixed.
要是你想弥补
If you wanted things fixed,
或许你应该回到过去
maybe you should have gone back in time
别让我哥哥死掉
and stopped my brother from dying.
你要我改变时间线去救丹堤
You want me to change the timeline to save Dante?
你有什么理由呢  他又不是你哥哥
Why would you do that? It's not like he's your brother.
超能力者提醒  得走了
Meta-human app. We gotta go.
在博德路发现
极速者
记得我吗  闪电侠
Remember me, Flash?
克拉里斯
Clariss?
你还真记得啊  闪电侠
Oh, you do remember, Flash?
很好
Good, yeah.
因为我也记得一切了
Because I remember everything, too.
-你怎么会在这里  -这不重要
- How are you here? - It doesn't matter.
你看  重要的是
You see, what does matter
我知道你的小秘密了
is that I know your little secret.
你改变了时间线
You changed the timeline.
因为如果我没记错
Because if I recall correctly,
我另一次生命中唯一的极速者
the only Speedsters in my other life
是我还有那个闪电小子
were me and that smartass Kid Flash,
直到你出现  夺走了我的一切
until you showed up and stole everything from me!
我没有夺走你的什么  克拉里斯
I didn't steal anything from you, Clariss.
我只是想让一切恢复
I-I was just trying to put things back
过去本来的样子
to the way they're supposed to be.
这就是我的生活本来的样子
This is how my life is supposed to be!
这么多年  我总觉得失去了点什么
For years, I felt like something was missing.
现在我知道原因了
And now I know why.
我很抱歉
Well, I'm sorry.
我不是故意想伤害你的
I didn't mean to do this to you.
但你还是伤害了我
Yeah, well, you did.
现在我来了
And here I am.
你的竞争者  又回来了
Your Rival, back again.
相信我  闪电侠  这一次
Believe me, Flash, this time,
你就不能那么轻易的夺走我的生活了
you're not gonna steal my life so easily.
我们终于摆脱了极速
We finally get rid of Zoom,
结果现在又出现一个邪恶极速者
and there's another evil Speedster?
这人又是谁啊
Who is this guy, now?
这个我知道
I can help you with that.
我终于拿到了
I finally got the results back
早上巴里给我
from the test I ran on the husk
用以检测的样本结果
that Barry gave me this morning.
很奇怪  因为上面没有暗物质痕迹
And it's weird, because there's no traces of dark matter,
但是却有速度力量的痕迹
but there are traces of the Speed Force.
爱德华·克拉里斯
这是那个极速者身上拿到的吗
And that's the husk from this Speedster?
看来是的  他叫
Appears so. His name is--
爱德华·克拉里斯
Edward Clariss.
巴里说的居然完全正确
And somehow Barry is exactly right.
爱德华·克拉里斯
我能跟你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you for a second?
好
Yeah.
尖端科研实验室
S.T.A.R. Labs isn't the only one
不是唯一能调取城市监控的地方
with access to the city's security cams.
显然这个人认识你
It's pretty obvious that this guy knows you.
你打算告诉我到底怎么回事吗
You want to tell me what that's about?
这就是你最近行为古怪的原因吧
This is why you've been acting so weird lately--
开始让我和爸爸和好
trying to get me and my dad talking again,
骗我们今晚一起吃饭
tricking all of us into dinner tonight--
因为你有事没告诉我们
because you're keeping something from us.
你得告诉我到底是怎么回事  巴里
You need to tell me what is going on, Barry.
马上
Right now.
要是你骗我
And if you lie to me...
那我们之间  就没有可能了
this thing between us, it cannot happen.
你说得对  抱歉  我
You're right, and, uh, I'm sorry, I--
这一切都因我而起
I did this. All of this.
都怪我  我在想办法补救
It's my fault and I've been trying to fix it.
但我想现在办法只有一个
But I think that there's only one way to do that now.
抱歉  爱瑞丝
I'm sorry, Iris.
闪电侠
Flash?
Flash.
把这身换上
Here, put these on.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
这是哪
Where are we?
中城的摩托餐厅
Motorcar Diner in Central City.
我是问这是哪一年
Yeah, I meant what year?
1998年
1998.
想吃点东西吗  我可是饿死了
Care to get something to eat? 'Cause I'm starved.
这里的咸牛肉土豆泥最好吃
The corned beef hash here is the best I've ever had.
这就是你把我拽出神速力的原因
This is why you pulled me out of the Speed Force?
-就为请我吃顿饭吗  -是因为你又要
- Buy me a meal? - Because you were about to
跑去重置你打乱的时间线了
reset the timeline again after screwing it all up.
我可什么都知道
Oh, yeah, I know about that.
-你怎么  -在你
- How did you-- - After your
第一次见我产生那么微妙的反应后
not-so-subtle reaction when you first met me...
哈利跟我说了极速和你妈妈
Harry told me all that happened with Zoom and your mom
以及你父亲的事  所以我决定
and your dad, so I decided
要看着你一点
I'd keep my eye on you for a bit.
-他跟你说了别的吗  -说了
- He tell you anything else? - He did.
我是你父亲的二重身
I'm your father's doppelganger.
很抱歉
Sorry about that.
只是很奇怪
It's just... really weird.
我知道  你还很伤心
And really sad, too... I'm sure.
失去生命中重要的人
Having a loss like that in your life,
我懂你为什么想抹掉那件事
I see why you'd wanna erase it.
谁不想救自己的父母
Who wouldn't try to save their parents?
我完全理解  巴里  非常理解
I understand that, Barry, completely.
但问题是  时间旅行是有代价的
But the thing is, there are consequences to time travel.
这些我之前都听过
I have heard all of this before.
你没听我说过
Not from me you haven't.
我不是什么只懂理论的学究  巴里
I'm not some Doctor with a theory, Barry.
我和你都是极速者  可以穿越时间
I'm a Speedster, like you, who's travelled in time,
也会犯你现在犯的错误
and made these same mistakes you are making right now.
我给你看些东西
Here, let me show you something.
-好了  听着  -听话  孩子
- Okay, you know what? - Humor me, kid.
-看这个咖啡杯  -好吧
- This coffee cup right here. - All right, yeah.
想象这是时空连续体
Think of it as the space-time continuum.
不管回到哪段时间  杯子都会碎
Whenever you go back in time it breaks.
-现在... -够了  我...
- Now... - For real? I mean--
你可以重置时间线  可以设法补救
you can reset the timeline, you can try to fix it,
但不管你多努力...
but no matter how hard you try...
都回不到原来的样子了
It's never gonna be exactly how it was.
虽然我之前不知道
Look, I've learned all this stuff
但这些道理我都懂
that I didn't know before, okay?
-我不会犯同样的... -错误
- I'm not gonna make the same... - Mistakes.
你刚刚怎么说的
Yeah, what you just said right there?
那是穿越时间的悖论
That is the paradox of time travel,
也是人生的悖论
and also the paradox of life.
早知如此  就不会这样了
I mean, if I only knew then what I know now.
如果不能回去补救因我而起的事
Why have these powers if I can't go back
我要这超能力有何用
and fix what I broke?
我们不是神  我们是凡人
We're not gods, we're men,
只是机缘巧合拥有了这超能力
who, for whatever reason, have been given extraordinary abilities.
你应该问自己
The question you need to ask yourself is,
你会成为怎样的英雄
what kind of hero are you gonna be?
是在你每次犯错之后
Are you just gonna take a do-over
都重来一次进行补救
every time you make a mistake?
还是接受这一切  向前看
Or will you live with them and move forward?
巴里在哪
Where's Barry?
我有事要跟你们说
I need to tell you all something.
事情真相
The truth.
什么的真相
The truth about what?
好吧
Okay, um...
极速杀了我父亲之后
after Zoom killed my dad,
我们打败他之后
after we defeated him, um...
我当时状态很不好
I wasn't in a great space,
以为补救的唯一办法就是
and I felt like the only way I could fix that was
穿越回去救下我母亲
to run back in time and save my mom.
你从逆闪手中救下你母亲了
You stopped the Reverse-Flash from killing your mom?
对
Yeah.
等等  那她还活着
Wait, so, is she alive?
有几个月她算还活着
She was. For a few months.
我跟我父母住在一起
I lived with her and my dad.
过了一段截然不同的生活
I had a completely different life.
大多数时候我连闪电侠都不是
I wasn't even The Flash for most of it.
我不懂了
I don't understand.
你创造了另一个世界
You created a whole other existence.
这怎么可能
How is that possible?
好吧
Okay, um...
我来画个  这是时间线
I'll do the-- this is the timeline.
这是我们现在存在的时间点
This is the point that we exist on it right now.
这就是我母亲被杀的时间点
This past point is where my mom was murdered.
我救下她  创造了新的世界
So when I saved her, I created a new reality.
新的时间线
A new timeline.
-我生活在  -镜像宇宙
- I was living in-- - A mirror universe.
它似乎被称为闪点
It's called a Flashpoint, apparently.
但你决定要离开那世界  为什么
But you decided to leave it. Why?
那里的生活开始失控
That life started to spin out of control.
克拉里斯这家伙
This guy, Clariss,
他在那也是极速者
he was a Speedster there, too.
他叫竞争者
He was known as the Rival.
惹了很多麻烦
He caused a lot of problems.
所以
So, um...
我决定再次穿越回去
I decided to run back in time again
让事情
and let things happen
按预期发展  希望能够
as they were supposed to, in hopes of...
重置时间线  但是
resetting the timeline, but...
-但是怎么了  -但是
- But what? - But, um,
我回来后  一切还是变了样
when I came back, things weren't the same.
你是说我们变了
You mean people. Like us.
对  对
Yeah, yeah.
我创造了另一条时间线
I created another timeline.
就是我们现在生活的时间线
Uh, it's the one we're living in now.
跟上一条时间线差不多
It's not as different as the last one.
基本相同  但跟我亲近的人
Not in large ways, but in some ways,
有些小事情  重要的事情
in smaller ways, and, uh, meaningful ways
还是跟之前不一样了
for all of you or anybody that's close to me.
我永远也没法补救了
And I can't ever really put it back together.
巴里  这可有得消化了
Barry, that's a lot to take in.
没错
Yeah, it is.
在那个世界我们父女俩
We got along in that other life,
关系很好吧
my dad and I, didn't we?
难怪你做这么多的努力
That's why you've been working so hard
想让我们和好
to get us talking again.
好吧  这样  我会告诉你们
Okay, here's the thing. Um, I will tell you
哪里不一样
what's different,
每一个人  如果你们想知道的话
all of you, if you wanna know.
但是你们必须带着这些不同继续生活下去
But you have to live with those differences
因为我不能再改变历史了
because I can't change it again.
但是至少你们能知道哪里不同
But at least you'll know.
你们都值得拥有这个机会
And you all deserve that choice.
所以你的亲人去世了
So you decided it was okay to change things
改变历史就可以
when someone in your family dies,
而我的亲人去世就...
but when it's someone in my family...
我去和他谈谈
I'm gonna go talk to him.
你在忙什么
What are you working on?
这是我战衣的手套
These are the gauntlets for my suit.
你什么都不知道  是不是
And you probably know nothing about that, do you?
我真的很努力了  西斯科
I'm really trying here, Cisco.
巴里  我才是在努力的那个
Barry, I'm the one who's been trying.
我一直都在试着
I've been trying this whole time
让你为我做这一件事
to get you to do this one thing for me,
但你一直说  "西斯科  不行
but you kept saying, "No, Cisco.
我不能这么做  我再也不能这么做了"
I can't, Cisco. I would never do that, Cisco."
然后你却告诉我  你自己这么做了
And now you're telling me you went and did it for yourself.
你没听我说吗
Were you listening?
事情变得很糟糕  真的很糟糕
It -- it went bad. It went really bad.
我才不管
I don't care!
至少我哥哥还会活着
At least I'd have my brother back.
是啊  你哥哥还会活着
Yeah, you would have him back,
但是就因为如此  其他人也许会遭遇
but because of it, somebody might have something
发生在丹堤身上的
happen to them that's just as awful
这种不幸  相信我
as what happened to Dante, and trust me,
你的良心是会受到谴责的
you don't want that on your conscience.
这是一个很沉的心理负担
It's a heavy burden to bear.
我不知道这句话我说了多少遍了
And I don't know how many times I've said this, but...
关于丹堤的事  我真的很遗憾
I'm really sorry about Dante, man.
再遗憾也改变不了事实
Sorry doesn't change anything.
确实不能  但是我不能回到过去
No, it doesn't, but I can't go back.
我不能改变历史了
I can't change it.
我能做的只有向前看
All I can do is move forward.
我希望你也能做到
I really hope you can, too.
我需要你的帮助
Hey, um, I need your help.
这七个字好像最近
It's the four words I seem to hear you
经常听你说呀  巴里
most often say, Barry.
还有"我讨厌这个家伙"这七个字
That and, "I hate that guy."
不过我也不喜欢你  所以...
Which, the feeling's mutual, so...
这对你来说肯定很难做到
This is gonna be hard for you,
但是  就这一小会儿
but I just, for a second,
我需要你把我们当做是朋友
need you to imagine that we're actually friends.
我做不到
Can't do it.
友好点总行了吧
Friendly.
还是很难啊  巴里
Equally as challenging, Barry.
我尽量吧
But I'll give it a whirl.
你想要什么
What are you after?
我想看关于
I need to read your report
-其中一个外壳的报告  -哪一个
- on one of the husks. - Which one?
今天早上这个  爱德华·克拉里斯
The one from this morning. Edward Clariss.
-爱德华·克拉里斯  -是的
- Edward Clariss? - Yeah.
-为什么  -能帮我破手上的案子
- Why? - May help me figure out a case I'm working on.
外壳的
Well, the nutshell is,
玻尿酸比正常水平高
the hyaluronic acids were found to be above normal.
雄性激素降解异常缓慢
Androgen degradation atypically low.
细胞再生速度难以置信地快
Cellular regeneration seemed to occur at a staggering rate.
和我们之前发现的
It's quite a bit different
外壳都不一样  就这样
from the previous husks that we found. That's about it.
我能不能  我能不能就看一眼
Could I -- could I maybe just take a peek at it?
抱歉  我要看一下才知道
I'm sorry, it's just something I need to see
是不是我想找的
to know what I'm looking for.
-可以  -太棒了  谢谢
- Sure. - Great, thank you.
为什么这上面写的发现尸体的地点是
Wait, why does this say the body's place of discovery
威廉姆森区
was Williamson
而其实是在利伍德路的海边发现的
when it was found on the waterfront in Leawood?
尸体最后被冲到了利伍德路
The body ended up in Leawood.
今天早上有一股很强的洋流
There was a strong current this morning,
很有可能洋流是从威廉姆森发源的
so chances are that it originated from Williamson.
就在普雷斯科特锯木厂附近
Somewhere near the old Prescott sawmill.
-看完了  -是  谢谢
- You done? - Yeah, uh, yes. Thank you.
闪电侠  你又找到我了
You found me again, Flash.
我还在想这次你要花多久才想出来
I wondered how long it'd take you this time to figure it out.
也不是很难
Wasn't too hard.
不过我看你这次没带小跟班来
I see you didn't bring your little sidekick with you, though.
-就只有我  -那真遗憾
- Nope. Just me. - That's too bad.
我可带了帮手来
I brought one.
对了  闪电侠
Oh, and Flash? A little, uh,
感到颤抖也是正常的
quaking in your boots wouldn't be inappropriate.
然后
So?
他改变了我们的生活  爱瑞丝
He changed our lives, Iris.
而且还对我们保守这个秘密
And he kept that secret from us.
你觉得我们应该就这么原谅他吗
You really just want us to just be okay with that?
我的意思  沃利  他犯了错
All I'm saying, Wally, is that he made a mistake.
-是啊  -西斯科  为了保护爱的人
- Yeah, he did. - Cisco, we all make mistakes
我们都会犯错的
to protect the people that we love.
为了保护你的哥哥
I mean, you told Captain Cold that Barry was The Flash
你告诉了寒冷队长巴里是闪电侠
in order to protect your brother.
好吧  也不是什么值得骄傲的事情
Okay. Not my finest moment.
正是如此  这只是那一刻做的一个决定
That's my point. It was one decision made in one moment.
一个撕心裂肺的时刻
One very heart-wrenching moment.
我们就像是一家人  不是吗
Look, guys, we're like a family here, okay?
有时候家人之间也会因为搞砸事情而生气
And sometimes families get mad at each other for screwing up.
我太了解这种感受了
I know that all too well.
但是家人也会原谅彼此
But they also forgive.
因为过了一段时间  想起这些事情
Because after a while, it just seems silly
你会觉得好可笑
when you stop and think about it.
爱瑞丝说得对
Guys, Iris is right.
我们都有秘密
We all have secrets.
我们都搞砸过
We've all screwed up, but this is Barry
但是这可是巴里啊
we're talking about.
他好像有麻烦了
Who apparently is in trouble.
你又是谁
And who are you?
我是炼金术师
I am Alchemy.
你想做什么
Okay, well, what do you want?
帮助人们发掘他们真正的潜力
To help people achieve their true potential...
就像他一样
such as he has.
你为什么要这么做
And why are you doing this?
我在为这个世界做准备
Because I'm preparing this world.
还记得上次在这里发生什么吗  闪电侠
Remember what happened here last time, Flash?
我死了
It's where I died.
我不会浪费这第二次机会的
And I'm not gonna waste this second chance I've been given.
这次  我要让你看看谁才是世上最快
This time, I'm gonna show you who's the fastest man alive.
巴里  巴里
Barry? Barry!
他的通讯设备无法使用了
His coms aren't working.
他在普雷斯科特锯木厂
He's at the Prescott Mill.
闪电侠
普雷斯科特锯木厂
就在附近
That's right around the corner.
我们得做点什么
We gotta do something.
玩得还开心吗  闪电侠
Having fun yet, Flash?
因为我可是开心极了
'Cause I'm having a blast.
是时候再找个新对手了
Time to look for a new rival.
离我朋友远点
Stay away from my friend.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉这么久才赶来
Sorry it took so long.
你来得刚刚好
You were just in time.
什么都没有  哪里都没提到过炼金术师
Nothing. No mention of Alchemy anywhere.
没有戴着面具的超能力修士
No mask-wearing monk metas.
连沾边的都没有
Not even close.
我在中城警局的记录里
I didn't find any known aliases
也找不到任何相关的已知化名
in any of the records at CCPD.
克拉里斯也死不交代
And Clariss won't say anything either.
好吧  先把他关着  是炼金术师
All right, well, keep at him. Alchemy is the one
恢复了克拉里斯的速度
that gave Clariss back his speed.
他某种程度上有点像医生  你们不觉得吗
He's kinda like a doctor, that way, don't you think?
拜托  别假装"炼金术师医生"
Come on, don't pretend like "Doctor Alchemy"
读起来不是朗朗上口
doesn't have a nice ring to it.
好吧  那解释了为什么
Okay, well, that explains why he didn't have
他的细胞里没有任何暗物质的痕迹
any traces of dark matter in his cells.
他的力量并不是来自于粒子加速器
He didn't get his powers from the particle accelerator,
而是从炼金术师那获得的
he got them from Alchemy.
你说的什么
What was that?
炼金术师医生
Doctor Alchemy.
他是怎么做到的
How could he do that?
我不知道  但我们得搞清楚
I don't know, but we need to figure it out.
会有更多这种情况出现
There's gonna be more.
炼金术师  炼金术师医生说他在
Alchemy-- Doctor Alchemy said that he is
给这个世界做准备
preparing this world.
Preparing the world?
为了什么  比如基督再临或者其他什么吗
For what? Like, the second coming or something?
我觉得所有在闪点拥有超能力的人
I think that everyone that had powers in Flashpoint
都会找回他们的超能力
is gonna get them back.
我们已经找到四具外壳了
Well, we already found four other husks,
也就意味着现在中城里
which means there's at least that many
至少有同样数量的超能力者在游荡
running around Central City right now.
我们得在他改变更多人的人生前找到他
We need to find him before he changes more people's lives.
说到改变人生
Speaking of changing lives,
我们都讨论过了  巴里  我们不想知道
we all talked about it, Barry, and we don't want to know
我们在闪点的人生是怎样的
what our lives were like in Flashpoint.
你确定吗
You sure?
引用哈利的至理名言
To quote the wise words of Harry,
"这样做意义何在呢  巴里"
"What's the point, Allen?"
我得赶去警局了
I gotta get to the precinct.
能顺带路过一下吉特咖啡店吗
Stop by Jitters on the way?
行啊  包在我身上
Yeah, it's on me.
太好了  那我也跟你们一起走
Oh, good. Then I'm coming, too.
我只是在想
Yo, um, I've just been thinking that
那真的挺酷的
it was pretty cool
像昨晚那样有人和我一起搭档
having someone out there with me last night.
我不知道  也许我们可以
And, I don't know, maybe we could
偶尔像那样搭档一下
make that a thing every once in a while.
在我开始那样做之前
I-I got some things to work on
我还有些其他事情要忙
before I start doing that.
好的
Yeah.
或许将来某一天吧
Maybe someday.
感觉还是相当棒的
It'd be pretty bitchin'.
很高兴看到所有事情都开始
Glad to see everything's starting to
重回正轨了
get back to the way it was.
是啊  我是说
Yeah. I mean...
大部分
mostly.
你没什么好担心的  凯特
You have nothing to worry about, Cait.
我整理了所有人的情况  其实  你是唯一
I think out of everyone, actually, you're the only one
在我干扰了时间线之后没有受到影响的人
that wasn't really affected when I messed with the timeline.
我是说  除非你私下里
I mean, unless you're secretly moonlighting
是位眼科医生
as an ophthalmologist.
-一位什么  -我开玩笑的  没什么
- A what? - Kidding, nothing.
只是个闪点玩笑  回头见
Just a Flashpoint joke. I'll see you later.
那是什么
What's that?
那是爱德华·克拉里斯的最终调查报告
That's the finished Edward Clariss report.
或者我是不是应该叫他竞争者
Or should I say The Rival?
至少  闪电侠昨晚把他扔进
At least, that's what The Flash called him
铁山监狱的时候是这么叫他的
last night when he took him into Iron Heights.
我觉得你也许想看一下
I thought you might want to see it.
你知道的  和你另外一件案子有关
You know, to do with your other case.
实际上  结果两者并没有什么关联
Actually it turns out there was no connection.
你知道吗  我得问问你
You know, I have to ask you.
-你是怎么知道他的名字的  -什么
- How did you know his name? - What?
昨天  你过来找我要
Yesterday, you came in and you asked
爱德华·克拉里斯的调查报告
for Edward Clariss' report,
但我没告诉你
but I didn't tell you
那具外壳属于谁  所以那就意味着
who that husk belonged to, so that means
你昨天出现在犯罪现场的时候偷走了一份样本
you stole a sample when you showed up to my crime scene.
你是如何做到的
How did you do that?
我
I--
你可真会装好人  是吧
You've really got this good guy routine thing down, haven't you?
而且大家还都买账了
And everyone just buys it.
你有点不对劲  艾伦
There is something not right about you, Allen.
他们看不出来  但我看出来了
They don't see it... but I do.
-是这样吗  -没错
- Is that right? - Yes.
你知道我为什么一直不喜欢你  对吗
You know why I don't actually like you, don't you?
我不信任你
I don't trust you.
而我不喜欢我不信任的事物
And I don't like things that I don't trust.
明天见  室友
See you tomorrow, roomie.
我想着你估计会在这里
I was hoping you'd be here.
是啊  我刚和我爸把
Yeah. Dad and I just polished off
埃丝特祖母的面条狼吞虎咽掉
Grandma Esther's noodle dish.
你有给我留一点吗
Oh, did you leave me some?
你来得太慢了  闪电侠
Too slow, Flash.
那么你们现在
So you guys are...?
我们和好了
We're good.
你确定你不想知道另一条时间线的事情吗
Are you sure you don't wanna know about the other timeline?
不想  我猜  在我脑海里  不管你去哪
No, I guess, in my mind, wherever you go,
你永远都是巴里
you'll always be Barry,
而我永远都是爱瑞丝
and I'll always be Iris.
而且我们总是能找到对方
And we always find each other.
你失败了
You failed.
你失败了  克拉里斯
You failed, Clariss.
对不起  请
I'm sorry. Please...
再让我试一次
let me try again.
炼金术师
Alchemy!
不  不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no.
不
No!